[
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9901_Yonas_Age",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"How old are you, really?\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Much too old to remember how old I am. Human lives may be eternal on this island, but human memories are not. Perhaps it’s how we stay sane. \\n\\nI hope you, too, live long enough to forget.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9901_Yonas_Books",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"You must really like books.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "The written word, what a marvelous invention. So much more reliable than memory. \\n\\nWould you like to borrow one of my books? It would be nice to have someone to discuss literature with…besides the fish, of course.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9901_Yonas_BecomingSoulwarden",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"What's it like, becoming a Soulwarden?\"",
        "NPCResponse": "It's been so long, I can hardly remember being anything else. Let's see… \\n\\nI do remember shivering with a bone-deep cold, feeling like I'd never be warm again…but that went away after a while.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9901_Yonas_SoulwardenFate",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"What happened to the other Soulwardens?\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Despair took them. There was a great war, and we lost. We ran, but I was the only one to outrun that fate. \\n\\nForgive me. It's been five hundred years, but it still feels too soon.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9901_Yonas_Fort",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"Do you know this place?\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Yes…I think so. Memories are starting to come back to me, little by little. \\n\\nI think this used to be a Soulwarden fort. I think this used to be home.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9901_Yonas_Friends",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"What were the other Soulwardens like?\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Complex, brave, frustrating, wonderful. I remember Ezra and his clever toys, Lilith and her lovely voice. Pravin, with his practical jokes. \\n\\nWhat I wouldn't give, to hear them laugh again.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9901_0021_AmrineSkip",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"I'd still like to hear about it.\" [Solo Option]",
        "NPCResponse": "As you wish. The essence of a Heartgem is derived from the same elements that power the Ancient Guardians.\\n\\nIf you can collect these substances from certain Guardians, you can forge a Heartgem for yourself. Good luck.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9915_Researcher1_Repellent",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"I, uh, have something for you.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Wow, urine! Just what I needed!",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9916_Researcher2_Repellent",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"Do you need some bear repellent?\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Did Theo finally figure out the formula? Thank science for that…",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9917_Researcher3_Repellent",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"Surprise! I made you some bear repellent.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Ugh, this smells terrible. \\n\\n\\The things I do for data...",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9918_Researcher4_Repellent",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"I have some bear repellent for you.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Ah, it's almost a shame. I think the bears were about to accept me, maybe.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9907_AEVillager1_Offering",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"Please, take this fish.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Mmm. This is a very fine fish. It's been so long since I was brought an offering… \\n\\nHere, have my blessing.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9908_AEVillager2_Offering",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"Please, have this memento.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "I wanted to know…how humans hold their pack. \\n\\nI wanted to learn…how creatures who forget, remember. \\n\\nI see now that they store their memories in things they make…very clever. \\n\\nThank you. Take my blessing.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9906_Shamaness_Offering",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"Please, take this plant food I made.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "the tempest spreads corruption shades the sun \\n\\nmy people cannot make the food they need \\n\\nthrough crafting arts their suffering undone \\n\\nmy blessing cede",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9903_Emile_FactionSame",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"I'm in the Covenant, too.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Yes, I could tell just by looking at you. The light of the Spark shines from you, and brings me hope. \\n\\nIf you find yourself struggling in darkness, I will do my best to help. Many Sparks together do not waver.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "Covenant",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9903_Emile_FactionRival",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"I'm not in the Covenant.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Rest easy, my friend. I have no intent to fight you; power struggles don't interest me. \\n\\nIn my opinion, any person who seeks to protect others, carries the Spark in their hearts.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "Syndicate",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9903_Emile_Epilogue",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"We did it, Emile.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Well, what do you know, {playerName}? We won. \\n\\nYou're the real thing, a real hero. I'm proud to have shared this journey with you. \\n\\nYonas would be proud, too. \\n\\nFirst drink is on me!",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9903_Emile_Origins1",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"How did you first come to Aeternum?\"",
        "NPCResponse": "I was duped. I thought I was part of a great cause, a holy mission. Story of my life, really.  \\n\\nThe other knights and I were chasing relics stolen from Jerusalem by sea, and by sea, like fools, we pursued them.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9903_Emile_Origins2",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"I take it you didn't find the relics.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "I'm not sure they ever even existed. Our knight commander turned out to be… not a trustworthy man.\\n\\nAfter a storm, we ended up shipwrecked on a strange beach. Many drowned, but I've always been a strong swimmer.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9903_Emile_Origins3",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"You had luck on your side.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Huh. Is it the lucky man who outlives every cause he’s ever joined? Emile the Lucky, they can call me. \\n\\nBut enough gloom, I think. Aeternum offers new causes, and eternal life, to boot. Both of us are very lucky.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9905_Rima_FactionSame",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"I'm a Marauder, too.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "I'm not surprised. Though some join the Marauders seeking strength in numbers, the best of us know that true strength lies in independence. \\n\\nAnd I sense a strong independent streak in you.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "Marauder",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9905_Rima_FactionRival",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"I'm not a Marauder.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Are we rivals, then? Shall we duel? (chuckles) \\n\\nLet's leave politics to the politicians. I am merely a poet, and you… I'm still trying to figure out what you might be.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "Covenant",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9905_Rima_Epilogue",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"We did it, Rima.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "You were wonderful, {playerName}. I knew I wasn't wrong about you. \\n\\nHave you met Ixia? I just love the way she speaks. So melodic. \\n\\nI'm thinking of asking her to collaborate on a song with me. Maybe one about you…",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9905_Rima_Origins1",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"How did you first come to Aeternum?\"",
        "NPCResponse": "It's a long and thrilling story. In the dead of night, on a ship bound for Tripoli, I escaped my bonds and dove overboard into the cold Mediterranean Sea. \\n\\nI expected to die, but instead, I washed up on Aeternum's shore.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9905_Rima_Origins2",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"You jumped overboard on purpose?\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Yes, to escape a fate worse than death - marriage, to an old man I'd never met. \\n\\nThe Sultan's men dragged me onto that ship. They thought they had me trapped, beaten… but they did not know me.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9905_Rima_Origins3",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"The Sultan forced you to marry?\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Yes, although he didn't want to. He was a good man, mostly, and a generous patron of my music, back in Constantinople. \\n\\nBut after I stabbed that prince, he faced great political pressure to make me disappear.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9905_Rima_Origins4",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"You stabbed a prince?\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Well, not fatally. He challenged me to a duel after I stole away Fatma, his fiancée. He was so angry… Is it my fault that my beautiful Fatma preferred me over that joke of a prince? \\n\\nOh, Fatma… I wonder if she ever did marry…",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9904_Theo_Epilogue",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"We did it, Theo.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "The Angry Earth language is fascinating. I'm working on an Angry Earth-to-Aeternian phrasebook! \\n\\n'Hello! My name is Theo. May I study you?' \\n\\nI hope that both humans and Angry Earth will be able to learn from one another!",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9904_Theo_Origins1",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"How did you first come to Aeternum?\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Providence! Destiny! The hand of Lady Fortuna herself! \\n\\n…or so I would say, if I weren't a man of rationality. Still, as the cannonballs hit the ship, and the water rose, I admit I raised a prayer or two.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9904_Theo_Origins2",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"Who attacked your ship?\"",
        "NPCResponse": "The Spanish, I think? I don't really follow politics. \\n\\nI was on my way to Oxford - to lecture on avian anatomy, you know - when the ship carrying me across the Channel suddenly… stopped carrying me across the Channel.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9904_Theo_Origins3",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"So, your ship sank?\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Presumably. That's what ships do, when they've got big holes in them. \\n\\nDon't you see? Everything acts according to observable, rational principles! Ships sink, birds fly, and azoth… well, it must have rules, as well.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9904_Theo_Origins4",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"What if azoth doesn't have rules?\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Inconceivable! Just because we don't understand the rules yet doesn't mean they don't exist. It's a scientist's job to reveal them. \\n\\nYes, there is so much to learn, and all the time in the world to do it!",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9921_Walker_Origins1",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"Welcome to the Soulwardens.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Thank you kindly. I want to protect all people in Aeternum, not just my own faction. What higher calling could there be in this life?",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9922_Wayne_Origins1",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"Welcome to the Soulwardens.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Hey, thanks! I used to be Covenant, I got tired of all the faction drama back home. It's like, Corruption is coming. It doesn't care who got the best zingers at the last town hall meeting, you know?",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9923_Constance_Origins1",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"Welcome to the Soulwardens.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Yes, yes, thank you! It's no use just waiting around hundreds of years for Corruption to return. Only when we can truly understand it can we banish it for good!",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9924_Eliza_Origins1",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"Welcome to the Soulwardens.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "It was Samir's idea. He's always wanted to be a big hero. I had to come along to keep him from sacrificing himself nobly at the first possible opportunity.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9925_Samir_Origins1",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"Welcome to the Soulwardens.\"",
        "NPCResponse": "And only just in time! What would you have done without me, were the Tempest to attack tomorrow? \\n\\nIt was a lucky break for humanity, the day Commander Yonas recruited me!",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9919_MSQ_DepthsSkip",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"What's your idea? [Solo Option]\"",
        "NPCResponse": "Well, I've been thinking. Thorpe's trying to get in control of all of those Corrupted forces, and a lot of his loyalists are establishing a redoubt in Great Cleave.\\n\\nI bet if you went and embarrassed his lieutenants in combat he'd be willing to leave his nest to see for himself.\\n\\nI leak some information about your whereabouts and... I think that would do it to get that narcissist to come after you.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    },
    {
        "ConversationTopicId": "9902_MSQ_ExpeditionSkip",
        "PlayerPrompt": "\"What's your thought? [Solo Option]\"",
        "NPCResponse": "The Blight is subtle, maybe we should be too.\\n\\nThe birds tell me that the forces of the Empress muster on the docks. There, Generals guide the loading of cargo, bound for the fleet.\\n\\nIf you were to put the Blight Bombs into the cargo destined for the fleet. They'd do the work to defeat themselves.",
        "AchievementUnlock": "",
        "RequiredAchievement": "",
        "RequiredFaction": "",
        "RequiredLevel": ""
    }
]
